colorescience.com 2018-06-26

# Privacy Policy - Colorescience Mineral Makeup

This Privacy Policy is effective on October 25, 2017.

Your privacy is very important to us. This Privacy Policy details Colorescience’s commitment to respecting the privacy of our customers and visitors to our Website and our other Services.

This Privacy Policy describes how Colorescience collects, discloses, and uses the information you provide to us on our Website and our other Services. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time. When we make revisions, we will post them on the Services and update the “Last Revised” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If we make changes that are significant, we may use reasonable efforts to attempt to notify you, including by email or placing a prominent notice on the first page of the Website. Revisions will be effective immediately upon posting.

In conjunction with this Privacy Policy, you should also review our Terms of Use located at https://www.colorescience.com/terms-conditions for a more complete understanding of the rules governing our Services. Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings set forth in the Terms of Use.

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

In order to provide an efficient, meaningful and customized experience for you on the Services, we collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address and phone number
  * Billing Information such as credit card number and billing address
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number and password
  * Preferences Information such as product wish lists, marketing preferences, and order history
  * Email addresses of friends or other people you would like us to contact

We may also obtain information about you from other sources, including commercially available sources, such as social media platforms, data aggregators and cooperatives and public databases. We may combine the information we receive from and about you, including the information you provide to us, with information we receive from third parties, information we automatically collect (as explained above) and information provided or collected offline including when you use the Services.

For example, by registering for an Account, you may have the option to sign in using third party social networking websites ("Social Networks"), such as Facebook or Twitter. You may also have the option of connecting to Social Networks to complete your profile information and populate your Account with information from these networks. If you choose to sign in through these Social Networks or connect your Account to these Social Networks, we use the information you have already provided to such Social Networks in registering for an account with such Social Networks and which you have allowed such Social Networks to share with Colorescience, including, but not limited to, your first name, your user profile picture, your friends and contacts list, your gender, and the networks to which you belong (collectively, your "Submitted Information"). You expressly authorize us to collect and use your Submitted Information in connection with your use of the Services. You further acknowledge and agree that Colorescience may, but is not obligated to, maintain copies of your Submitted Information indefinitely, or delete any or all Submitted Information, at our sole discretion. We advise you to carefully read to the terms of use and privacy policies of Social Networks. It is your responsibility to read and accept the respective Social Networks policies prior to creating or signing into your Account through a Social Network.

As is true of most websites and similar services, we automatically gather information about your computer or device from which you access the Services, such as your IP address, browser type, time and date of visit, referring/exit pages and operating system. We may log this information for system administration, order verification, internal marketing and system troubleshooting purposes.

We use the information we collect from you to:

  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Assess your needs to determine suitable products
  * Send product updates or warranty information
  * Respond to customer service requests and provide you with live support
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter and marketing communications
  * Improve our Services and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Display content based upon your interests
  * Respond to your questions and concerns

To review and update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, contact us at the address listed at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. 

### Choice/Opt-Out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, updating your communications preferences in your Account by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link contained in any promotional email or contact us at the address listed at the bottom of this Privacy Policy (and put "Unsubscribe" or "Opt Out" in the subject line).

We may also send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our Services are temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. We may also send you transactional communications related to orders you place through the Services. For instance, we may send you an email to confirm that we have received your order, to update you on your shipping and order status, or to answer questions you may have about your order. Generally, you may not opt-out of these service-related announcements or transactional communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you may request that Colorescience disable your account by contacting us at the address listed below, or by contacting the Colorescience Concierge team at https://www.colorescience.com/customer-service. Please clearly label the subject line "Corrections / Disabling Account."

### Information Sharing (General)

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties, and we do not authorize the collection of our members' or visitors' personally identifiable information by any third parties for the third parties' use.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us in the operation of our Services or with our other business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. Such sharing includes:

sharing your billing and shipping information with payment processors such as Authorize.net and third-party logistics vendors that are assisting us in fulfilling orders you place through the Services,

sharing your personal information with third parties such as Crowdtwist, Inc. that assist us in maintaining and operating the Rewards Program, and

sharing your personal information with third parties such as media agencies or email service providers that are assisting us in sending direct marketing messages.

These companies are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information disclosed to them and otherwise to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy, and are prohibited from using Personal Information disclosed for any purpose other than as necessary to provide the applicable services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, an illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity, to investigate fraud or respond to a government request;
  * as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process; or
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We may share non-personal information (such as the number of daily visitors to a particular web page or the size of an order placed on a certain date or other aggregated usage data) with third parties such as advertising partners. This information does not directly personally identify you or any user. If Colorescience engages in a joint promotion with an affiliate and/or partner, we may share your personal information with our affiliate and/or partner to be used in relation to the promotion, and you will have the opportunity to opt-out out of such promotional communications.

If Colorescience is involved in a merger, acquisition or sale of all or a portion of its assets, or in the event that Colorescience goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, your personal information may be one of the assets that is transferred to or acquired by the third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Colorescience or its assets may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If any acquirer of Colorescience or its assets will use your personal information contrary to this Privacy Policy, you will receive prior notice.

### **Information Sharing (Lasting Beauty Rewards)**

  1. We may share the following information with “Colorescience Partners” (medical or other aesthetic practices carrying Colorescience products) for the purpose of enabling them to contact you, award points, and redeem coupons: 
    1. Your points balance and length of time as a member
    2. Digital and in-office coupons that are either available or that have been already used
  2. Additionally, Colorescience Partners are permitted to redeem your points on your behalf, in exchange for an in-office coupon to be used with that partner.
  3. If you either registered for LBR at, or were awarded points by a Colorescience Partner, we may provide to that Colorescience Partner: 
    1. Your contact details, which may include email address and phone number
    2. Your online and offline transactional history, including products previously purchased
  4. Colorescience will take reasonable measures to monitor and prevent abuse of this access, and will reverse transactions not authorized by you upon your request.
  5. Your mailing address, birthday, payment information, and other personal information other than 3.1 above will not be shared with Colorescience Partners.

### Public Communications Features

From time to time you may be able to participate in certain activities on the Services, such as forums, reviews, user opinions, chat rooms or bulletin boards (“Public Communications Features”), which give you the opportunity to communicate with Colorescience and other users of the Services. Be aware that when you volunteer information or create a public profile in the course of your participation in our Public Communications Features, you are also agreeing to allow certain aspects of your personal information to be made public. This includes your username, any personal information or images that you add to your signature, or any data or other information, including personal information, which you otherwise post to the public using such Public Communications Features. You acknowledge and agree that Colorescience does not review, censor, or in any manner control the content of these Public Communications Features. Consequently, Colorescience has no liability or responsibility for information made available through these Public Communications Features and you will be liable to Colorescience for any liability that we incur as a result of any information submitted by you in or through the Public Communications Features. 

### Web Tracking Technologies

We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags or other technologies to automatically collect certain information when you use our Services, or interact with our emails on or from our Services or other websites. This information may include your IP address, browser type, geolocation data, unique user ID, cell phone model, operating system and carrier, and Internet Service Provider. We also may collect information about your use of our Services, such as the number of times you return or visit the Services, whether you click-through, open, or forward links, emails, and ads, the URLs and webpages you've visited, sections of or content on pages of the Website on which you click or in which you are interested, the number of times you visit each webpage, what downloads and/or search queries you have made, how long you spent on particular sections of the Website and on the Services generally, and other website usage data. These technologies (including cookies on the Website) allow us to keep track of your order as you shop on our Services, recognize registered users when they visit, and provide registered customers with information and advertising that is more relevant to them. If you register with or order from us, we may use cookies or other technology to monitor and maintain information about how you use our Services and what you buy. If you do not register with or order from us, we may monitor and maintain information about your use of the Website in order to improve your shopping experience and provide you with more relevant products, content and advertising. Cookies

Cookies are small text files of information stored by the Internet browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not collect personal or confidential information and are not spyware. We may use cookies to collect browsing data to keep track of your preferences and profile information and to collect general usage and volume statistical information. You may set your Internet web browser to refuse cookies or to remove cookies from your hard drive.

### Web Beacons

Our Services contain electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

We may use a third party to gather information about how you and others use our Services. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated information to understand and optimize how our Services are used.

We may partner with third party ad network(s) to either display advertising on our Services or to manage our advertising on other websites. Our ad network partner(s) may use cookies and/or web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on our Services and other websites to provide you with targeted advertising based upon your interests. Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers.

We may also use services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”), to assist in providing the Services. Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyze how users use the Services. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Services (including your IP address) will be transmitted to, and stored by, Google on their servers. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Services, compiling reports on website activity for us and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Services. By using these Services, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We will not store your complete credit card information on our servers, but will only use an incomplete identifier (e.g., last four digits of your credit card number) to identify your Account. Any complete credit card information you choose to store in connection with your Account will be stored by our third party payment processing service providers such as Authorize.net.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Services, you can contact us at the address listed at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

### Targeted Advertising

Targeted Advertising (also known as online behavioral advertising) uses information collected on an individual's web browsing behavior such as the pages they have visited or the searches they have made. We may work with third parties by placing or accessing cookies in your browser when you visit this, or other, websites and thus being able to better serve you relevant, targeted advertising to you based on your viewing history.

### Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, you may request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, or to choose to opt out of such disclosure. To make such a request, please write to us at the address below.

### Children's Privacy

We do not intentionally collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen (13). If you are under the age of thirteen (13) you should not register, order, purchase or provide information to or from Colorescience. If you have knowledge that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has submitted Personal Information to us, please email us and we will remove that child's personal information from our files.

Correction to Your Personal Information or Disabling Your Account

You can (a) access, correct, or update your Personal Information, and/or (b) disable your online account to prevent any future purchases through that account. You can make these requests by contacting us at the address listed below, or by contacting the Colorescience Concierge team at https://www.colorescience.com/customer-service. Please clearly label the subject line "Corrections / Disabling Account." Do not email us your credit card information.

### Contact Information

You can contact us about this Privacy Policy by writing or emailing us at the address below:

©2017 Colorescience, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
